Guide to the Lantern Slide Collection [ca. 1860-1942] PR 70
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series I: General Lantern Slides
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--Chatham Square (Box 66)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--City Hall Park (Box 66)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--Cold Springs (Box 66)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--Collect Pond (Box 66)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--East River Park (Box 66)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--Elgin Botanical Garden (Box 66)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--Gramercy Square Park (Box 66)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--Madison Square Park (Box 66)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--Morningside Park (Box 67)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--Park (Box 67)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--Playground (Box 67)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--Polo Grounds (Box 67)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--Printing House Square (Box 67)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--Union Square Park (Box 67)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--Washington Square Park (Box 67)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Apartments (Box 67)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Farms (Box 68)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes (Box 68)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--A through K (Box 68)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--A through K (Box 69)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Astor House (Box 69)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Bayard House (Box 69)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Beekman House (Box 69)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Collonade Row (Box 70)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Collonade Row (Box 70)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Delafield House (Box 70)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Dyckman House (Box 70)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Fonthill (Box 70)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Franklin Mansion (Box 70)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Goelet Mansion (Box 70)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Gracie Mansion (Box 70)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Hamilton Grange (Box 70)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--L through Q (Box 70)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--L through Q (Box 71)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Morris-Jumel Mansion (Box 71)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Morris-Jumel Mansion, interiors (Box 71)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--R through V (Box 71)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--R through V (Box 72)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Schermerhorn House (Box 72)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Schermerhorn House (Box 72)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Smith's Folly (Box 72)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Stuyvesant House (Box 72)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Stuyvesant House, interiors (Box 72)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Stuyvesant House, interiors (Box 72)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--Ver Planck House, interiors (Box 73)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Residences--Houses and Homes--W through Z (Box 73)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Schools and Colleges (Box 73)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Schools and Colleges, by name (Box 73)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Schools and Colleges, by number (Box 74)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Schools and Colleges, interiors (Box 74)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Schools and Colleges--Columbia University (Box 74)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Schools and Colleges--General Theological Seminary (Box 74)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Schools and Colleges--New York University (Box 74)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Schools and Colleges--New York University, interiors (Box 74)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets (Box 74)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets (Box 75)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets (Box 76)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets, avenues by number (Box 76)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets, streets by number (Box 76)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets, unidentified (Box 76)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Battery Place (Box 76)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Bowery (Box 77)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Broad Street (Box 77)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Broadway--Below Battery Place (Box 77)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Broadway--Battery Place to Exchange Place (Box 77)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Broadway--Exchange Place to Wall Street (Box 77)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Broadway--Wall Street to Fulton Street (Box 77)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Broadway--Fulton Street to Chambers Street (Box 77)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Broadway--Chambers Street to Canal Street (Box 78)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Broadway--Canal Street to Houston Street (Box 78)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Broadway--Houston Street to Fourteenth Street (Box 78)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Broadway--Fourteenth Street to Twenty-third Street (Box 78)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Broadway--Above Twenty-third Street (Box 78)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Canal Street (Box 78)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Fifth Avenue (Box 78)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Fifth Avenue (Box 79)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Five Points (Box 79)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Mott Street (Box 79)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Park Avenue (Box 79)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Park Row (Box 79)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Riverside Drive (Box 79)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--Wall Street (Box 79)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Streets--William Street (Box 79)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Theaters (Box 79)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Theaters (Box 80)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Theaters, interiors (Box 80)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Theaters--Castle Garden (Box 80)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Theaters--Hippodrome (Box 80)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Theaters--National Theatre (Box 80)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Theaters--National Theatre (Box 80)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Theaters--Park Theatre (Box 80)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Transportation--Elevated Railroads (Box 80)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Transportation--Grand Central Depot (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Transportation--Pennsylvania Station (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Transportation--Pennsylvania Station, interiors (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Transportation--Railroads, trains (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Queens--Churches (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Queens--Residences--Houses and Homes (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Queens--Schools and Colleges (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Cemeteries (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Churches (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Commercial Buildings--Factories (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Commercial Buildings--Restaurants and Taverns (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Government and Public Buildings (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Government and Public Buildings--Courthouses (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Government and Public Buildings--Detention Facilities (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Government and Public Buildings--Forts--Fort Richmond (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Government and Public Buildings--Institutions--Sailor's Snug Harbor (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Hotels (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Industrial Facilities (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Monuments and Statues (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Parks and Squares (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Parks and Squares--Silver Lake (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Residences--Houses and Homes (Box 81)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Residences--Houses and Homes (Box 82)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Residences--Houses and Homes--Billiopp House (Box 82)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Residences--Houses and Homes--Fountain Homestead (Box 82)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Schools and Colleges (Box 82)
  - New York-NYC-Staten Island--Streets (Box 82)
  - New York-Stony Point (Box 82)
  - New York-Ticonderoga--Residences--Houses and Homes (Box 82)
  - New York-West Point--Constitution Island (Box 83)
  - New York-West Point--Parks and Squares (Box 83)
  - North Carolina (Box 83)
  - Pennsylvania (Box 83)
  - Rhode Island (Box 83)
  - South Carolina (Box 83)
  - Utah (Box 83)
  - Vermont (Box 83)
  - Virginia (Box 84)
  - Washington (Box 84)
- Series II: Songs
  Scope and Contents note
  Lantern slides which illustrate a song lyric. The song title, when known, is listed below.
  - Baby Face (Box 84)
  - Belong To Me (Box 84)
  - Bessie Dear (Sweet Bessie Dear?) (Box 84)
  - Bobb'n Up and Down (Box 84)
  - By the Old Oaken Bucket, Louise (Box 84)
  - Bygone Days (Box 84)
  - By the Silv'ry Rio Grand (Box 84)
  - City of Sighs and Tears (Box 84)
  - College Boys (Box 85)
  - Curfew Shall Not Ring To-Night (Box 85)
  - Daddy Has a Sweetheart (and mother is her name) (Box 85)
  - Dolly Dear (Box 85)
  - Down in Melody Lane (Box 85)
  - Dreami…(remainder is cut off) (Box 85)
  - Dreams Just Dreams (Box 85)
  - Fascinating Ragtime Glide (Box 85)
  - Fiddle Dee Dee (Box 85)
  - Finest May (Box 85)
  - Garden of Love, The (Take Me Back To?) (Box 86)
  - Georgia (Box 86)
  - Ghost of Violin (or The Ghost of the Violin) (Box 86)
  - Give me a small town Sweetheart (Box 86)
  - Go 'Way Mistah Moon (Box 86)
  - Golden Rod Flower of Liberty (Box 86)
  - Good By All (Box 86)
  - Good Old U. S. A., The (Box 86)
  - He Never Even Said Good-bye (Box 86)
  - Hearts and Eyes (Box 86)
  - Humming Bird (Box 86)
  - I Want Someone (to Flirt with Me? Or to Love Me?) (Box 86)
  - I Want to Be in Dixie (Box 86)
  - I will miss you girlie mine (Box 86)
  - I'm Afraid to Come Home (In the Dark?) (Box 86)
  - I'm Trying So Hard to Forget You (Box 86)
  - If I Had a Girl Like You (Box 87)
  - In the Good Old Fashioned Way (Box 87)
  - In the Land of Harmony (Box 87)
  - It Was Your Pleasing Smile (Box 87)
  - It's always June when you are in love (Box 87)
  - It's You, Pal (Box 87)
  - Just One Dearie (Box 87)
  - Just One Sweet Girl (Box 88)
  - Just Tell Her That I Loved Her Too (Box 88)
  - Kentucky Sue (or Sweet Kentucky Sue) (Box 88)
  - Lady Love (Box 88)
  - Leav's Were Falling (Box 88)
  - Let me prove my love to you (Box 88)
  - Let's build a bridge from your heart (Box 88)
  - Let's Buzz (Box 88)
  - Life Boat (Box 88)
  - Live in My Heart (Box 88)
  - Lonesome (Box 89)
  - Lonesome Land (Box 89)
  - Longest Way Round (Is the Sweetest Way Home) (Box 89)
  - Loving Man (Box 89)
  - Mammy's Shuffling Dance (Box 89)
  - Mary (Box 89)
  - Mary Was My Mother's Name (Box 89)
  - Mary You're a Big Girl (Box 89)
  - Mello-Cello Melody (Box 89)
  - Mid the Green Fields of Virginia (Box 89)
  - Mississippi Dippy Dip, The (Box 89)
  - Mother Old and Gray (Box 89)
  - My Alabama Rose (Box 89)
  - My Beautiful Rose (Box 89)
  - My Little Georgia Rose (Box 89)
  - My Little Lovin' Sugar Babe (Box 89)
  - My Love is Greater than the World (Box 89)
  - My Martha Jane (Box 90)
  - Nearer, My God, To Thee (Box 90)
  - Night and Day (Box 90)
  - Nobody's Little Girl (Box 90)
  - Oh That Loving Man? (Box 90)
  - Oh Why Why (Box 90)
  - Oh You Circus Day! (Box 90)
  - Oh You Little Bear (Box 90)
  - Put Your Arms Around Me, Honey (I Never Knew Any Girl Like You) (Box 90)
  - Ragtime Dream, The (Box 90)
  - Ragtime Major Sam (Box 90)
  - Ragtime Violin (Box 90)
  - Rainbow (Box 90)
  - Red Red Rose (Box 90)
  - Rock of Ages (Box 90)
  - Send for Me (Box 90)
  - She Was Bred in Old Kentucky (Box 91)
  - Sit on the Moon (Box 91)
  - Somebody is Getting It (Box 91)
  - Soul Kiss, The (Box 91)
  - Star Spangled Banner (National Anthem of U. S.) (Box 91)
  - Stay In Your Own Backyard (Box 91)
  - Stop! Stop! Stop! (Come over and love me some more) (Box 91)
  - Story of the Signal Man, The (Box 91)
  - Summer Girl, The (Box 91)
  - Sweetheart (Box 91)
  - Take Me to Roseland Oh My Beautiful Rose (Box 91)
  - Sweetheart (Rem.) (Box 91)
  - Take Me Up (With You ) Dearie. (Box 91)
  - That Dreamy Italian Waltz (Box 91)
  - That Hypnotizing Man (Box 92)
  - That Ragtime Goblin (Man/Rag?) (Box 92)
  - That Sorry D.? (Box 92)
  - Tie That Binds, The (Box 92)
  - Tis Not Always Bullets That Kill (Box 92)
  - Undertaker Man, The (Box 92)
  - Valley Flower (Box 92)
  - Volunteer Organist, The (Box 92)
  - When I Long for You (Box 92)
  - When Teddy comes marching home (Box 92)
  - When the Tide is Turning (Box 92)
  - When the Whippoorwill Sings Marguerite (Box 92)
  - When You Kiss an Italian Girl (Box 92)
  - When You Were Sweet Sixteen (Box 92)
  - When You're Lonesome (Box 92)
  - Why Don't You Try (a.k.a. The Rolling Chair Song) (Box 92)
  - Winter Time (Box 93)
  - With the girl of my leave (Box 93)
  - Women of Mumbles Head (Box 93)
  - You're Just too Sweet to Live (Box 93)
  - You've Got the Wrong Number, But You've Got the Right Girl (Box 93)
  - Zona (Box 93)
  - Untitled songs (Box 93)
  - Untitled songs (Box 94)
  - Untitled songs (Box 95)
- Series III: Announcements
  Lantern slides used in theaters for announcement and advertising purposes.
  - Announcements (Box 96)
  - Announcements (Box 97)